# **Gabil Gurbanov**

Tel: <u>+994 55 289 63 86</u> · Mail: <u>ggurbanov12098@ada.edu.az</u> · Github: <u>https://github.com/ggurbanov12098</u> E-Olymp: <u>https://www.eolymp.com/en/users/ggurbanov12098</u> Location: Baku, Surakhani, AZ1133

Graduate of Bacheolor degree in Computer Science (ADA). Enthusiastic learner in Cyber, Network, and Data Science. Ready to utilize my skills and passion to further the mission of a company. To get a challenging position at a recognized firm that will allow me to further my education, experience, and abilities. Find a responsible job opportunity where I can put my training and abilities to good use while contributing to the company's success. Technologically adept, programming languages, programs, and advanced computer skills. Bringing forth a positive attitude of the willingness and motivation to learn new skills and programs

#### **EDUCATION**

ADA University (Graduated) BS in Computer Science

Sep 2019 - June 2024

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ABB Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

## **Network Operations Center Analyst intern**

- Analyze network and other critical infrastructure using various monitoring tools and technologies, including Wazuh, Splunk, and Dynatrace.
- Support Active Directory services, ensuring secure and efficient user access to network resources in alignment with InfoSec industry standards.
- Respond to alerts, incidents, and service requests in a timely and efficient manner, ensuring minimal downtime for critical financial operations.
- Scripting to automate a number of NOC functions to help increase team efficiency.
- Process & update weekly and monthly NOC reports.

# BestComp Group Data Analyst

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

- Developed datasets for model training.
- Performed Data cleaning operations.
- Developed an OCR model for license number recognition Conducted research and prepared reports on various topics related to the company's operations and industry trends.
- Trained YOLOv5 object detection model for detecting license plates.

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Azerbaijani (Native)
- Russian (Fluent)
- English (Advanced)

#### **ACHIEVEMENT & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Academic Excellence, honored for outstanding academic performance qualifying for the Dean's List of High Performance in ADA
- Pre-finalist in the Republican Subject Olympiad (District-City stage) in Mathematics held by the Republic of Azerbaijan Ministry of Education on 04.02.2018
- Coursera: Foundations of Cybersecurity (Google)
- Coursera: Play It Safe, Manage Security Risks (Google)
- Coursera: Connect and Protect, Networks and Network Security (Google)
- Successful completion of Embedded Systems Pro Bootcamp
- Successful completion of Python Dev Pro Bootcamp
- Achievement for completing the mandatory requirements and for outstanding performance in ADA Employability Week by ABB and ATL Tech (seperately in 2022 and 2023)
- Pre-finalist in Critical Infrastructure Defence Challenge 2023 (CIDC 2023) / Team "Firewall Force"

#### **SKILLS**

#### Hard Skills:

- Programming & Scripting languages in Python, Java, JavaScript, C, Bash, PSQL
- CyberSecurity, Advanced Computer Networks, Big Data, Artificial Intelligence
- Microsoft Office tools and Cloud (Server), AWS
- Statistics and Mathematical Reasoning

#### Soft Skills:

- Adaptation to single and team work
- Proactive troubleshooter
- Communication

#### **VOLUNTEER**

- ADA Innovation Center
- Baku City Circuit (Formula 1)
- "Davam" Youth Center (IT club)
- Mars Academy / RoboGames (Lego Robotics)
- ASAN Service

#### REFERENCES

- Nariman Aliyev | Instructor at ADA : naliyev@ada.edu.az
- Orkhan Mammadov | Manager, Infrastructure Management at ADA : omammadov@ada.edu.az
- Samir Rustamov | Associate Professor, Director of BSCS Program : srustamov@ada.edu.az